Resumé of Robert W. Raftery cell: (626) 660-8311 email: braftery@protonmail.com 2038 Meridian Ave, #F South Pasadena, CA 91030

# **Summary**

Senior Developer with full web stack experience implementing Internet-facing websites. Developed and maintained database-driven web apps in Java J2EE hosted on RedHat Linux, Microsoft IIS/Active Server Pages (ASP) hosted on Microsoft Server, JSP-based websites using an enterprise Content Management System (CMS), and PHP hosted on RedHat Linux.

Possess excellent communication skills both written and oral. Proficient with full software development life cycle. Experienced at object-oriented analysis and design. Self-starter that thrives in a team environment.

# **Technology**

Experience using the following technologies.

Content Management System (CMS) SDL Tridion Enterprise CMS

# Object-Oriented Analysis & Design

UML Modeling, UML Sequence Diagrams, UML Class Diagrams, UML Package Diagrams

# Web Technologies

HTML 5/4.x/3.x, XHTML, CSS 2.x/1.x, MS JScript, Javascript, ECMA Script, jQuery, JSDoc, JsUnit, PHP, XML, XML DTD, XML Schemas (XSD), XSLT, XPath Expression

#### Web Platforms

JBoss Enterprise Server, IBM WebSphere Advanced Server (WAS 5), IBM Apache HTTP Server, IBM WSAD IDE, Apache Tomcat, Microsoft IIS ASP using JavaScript and VB-Script, Seagate Crystal Reports

#### Java J2EE

Java Servlets 2.3, Java JSP, Java EJB 2.0, EJB Session Beans, EJB CMP Entity Beans, Java Collections Package, Java Threads, Java Mail, Java Activation Framework (JAF), Java JDBC 2.0, JavaDoc, Jakarta Struts, Jakarta Log4J, Jakarta Commons components, Jakarta Commons RegEx (ORO), Apache Ant build scripts, JUnit to assist with unit testing

# Scripting Technologies

Microsoft HTML Application (HTA), cmd/bat file scripts on Win NT/2k, WSH (Windows Script Host) on Win2k using JavaScript and VB-Script, ksh (Korn Shell) on IBM AIX, bash (Bourne-Again Shell) on RedHat Enterprise Linux, sed/awk scripts, PHP

# Source Code Management

MKS Source Integrity, PVCS Source Code Management, Microsoft Visual Source Safe

# **Databases**

Oracle 11/10g/9i, Oracle SQL, Oracle SQL Views, Oracle SQLPlus, SQLPlus scripts, PL-SQL, MS-SQL 2000, T-SQL, MS-SQL UDF, SQL Views, Stored Procedures, SQL DML and DDL, MySQL

# **NO-SQL Databases**

Splunk, Lotus Notes

# Computer Systems

MS Windows, Mac OS X, RedHat Enterprise Linux, IBM AIX, IBM System 36, IBM AS400 (exposure), HP3000, HP3000-UX, HP Image database, HP Cobol, Ryan McFarland RM-Cobol

# None Of The Above

IBM WebSphere MQ, Lotus Script, MS VB 6, OLE2 and VB-Automation scripting of Microsoft Access, Microsoft Excel and Microsoft Word, Eclipse IDE

# **Employment**

2015 - 2016

Union Bank, Senior Developer Risk Management App Development Team

Responsible for support of 2 vendor applications: a fraud case management application and a fraud detection application, installation of new vendor software releases, maintenance of Informatica ETL (Extract-Transform-Load) jobs, develop and maintain Oracle SQL queries for ad-hoc reporting.

# 2013 - 2015

Union Bank, Senior Support Engineer

Responsible for 2<sup>nd</sup>/3<sup>rd</sup> level Production Support for 70 Internet-facing, database-driven Java J2EE web applications. Duties include incident management, triage incoming incidents, identify and coordinate with necessary technical support teams to drive to a timely resolution, investigate and gather the information necessary to handoff to the application team if appropriate, manage and document the incidents using the enterprise ticketing systems, drive reorganizing the information architecture of the departmental wiki, write/document Splunk queries to provide cross-application analysis and reporting, mentor junior team members, advise teammates on automating application validation scripting using Microsoft HTA (HTML Applications) and Java, onboard new applications for support by interviewing the application development team and documenting key support topics in the departmental wiki, represent Enterprise Application Support interests in Enterprise Change Management meetings.

Union Bank, Senior Developer for Content Management System and Web apps

Following is a list of Internet-facing websites owned and operated by Union Bank. The website content is maintained and published by the SDL Tridion Enterprise CMS system.

- www.unionbank.com
- www.hoabankers.com
- www.highmarkcapital.com

Responsible for designing and creating static HTML from comps and maintaining vendor-created HTML, for creating advanced Javascript scripts and maintaining vendor-supplied Javascript scripts, for designing, creating and implementing the components, component templates, page templates and other artifacts necessary to enable the Content Management Team to manage the previous list of websites and their content.

Responsible for designing, creating and implementing various reports and site management utilities implemented in ASP, ASP.NET, and Oracle SQL Views.

Responsible for rewriting the BLW application, (http://blw.unionbank.com/), an Internet-facing website responsible for displaying the nearest Bank branches, ATM's and various other services based on location information provided by the web visitor. The application is implemented in PHP and MySQL on the server-side and and uses the Google Maps API v2.0 and jQuery in the browser.

"Skinned" the output results from a Google Search Appliance using XSLT to conform to www.unionbank.com's look-n-feel and to conform to www.highmarkcapital.com's look-n-feel.

Responsible for prototyping new website www.highmarkcapital.com using XHTML, CSS and jQuery. The XHTML, CSS and Javascript logic from the mockup was then used by a team of 3 other developers and myself to create the Tridion Page Templates, Component Templates, Components and other artifacts to implement the final version to be turned-over to the Content Management Team for content entry and site creation.

### 2007 - 2008

Union Bank, Contract Developer

Created and implemented a Microsoft HTML Application (HTA) consisting of HTML, Dynamic HTML, JScript and Windows Script Host, (WSH). The purpose of the HTML Application was to secure a vendor application by strictly limiting the PC operator to making choices from a menu presented by the HTA. To that end the HTA automated the operator's manual processes and "front-ended" the vendor application.

2006 - 2007

Sabbatical

# 2005 - 2006

Union Bank, Senior Developer OEUA-IODA Application

OEUA-IODA is a customer-facing J2EE web application to enable external Bank customers to set up new users and administer existing users access to the Bank's Image-On-Demand web application. The application was developed using servlets and Enterprise Java Beans employing role-based J2EE security and digital certificates, XML, XSL, XML DTD, JavaScript, and CSS 2.0.

### 2004 - 2005

Union Bank, Senior Developer WRI Application

WRI (Returned Items on the Web), is a customer-facing J2EE web application that notifies Bank customers when a deposited item has been returned and enables the customer to display an image of the item as well as information about the returned item. Worked on the Welcome Page using Java Servlet, JSP, Enterprise Session Bean, Enterprise Entity Beans; created SQL scripts to assist with performance testing and functional testing; create SQL Views in Oracle 9i database to support automated customer notifications; performed analysis; coordinated testing and development with outside development groups; negotiated and documented functional and non-functional aspects of data feed with mainframe application.

Mentored team members in using the IBM AIX to implement, monitor, and test various parts of the application. Developed Unix Shell scripts to automate repetitive tasks. Created automated build scripts using Apache Ant and Windows 2000 shell scripts.

### 2003 - 2004

Union Bank, Senior Developer PPW Application

PPW (Positive Pay on the Web), is a customer-facing J2EE web application to enable customers to display information and images of the customer's positive pay items. Developed application-specific logging proxy to insulate the application from the logging implementation used. The log proxy used Jakarta Log4J. Also, created custom classes to extend the JDBC Appender for Log4J to enable fine-grained logging of specific object properties and a custom parser to support same.

Developed multi-threaded job scheduler component, in Java, for running various application-specific tasks. Used JUnit for unit testing. Assisted in creating automated build scripts using Apache Ant and Windows 2000 shell scripts.; Designed both components using UML diagrams.

# 2003 - 2003

Union Bank, Senior Developer MDCU Client

MDCU (Market Driven Contact Us), Enterprise service, implemented in Java, for capturing and routing customer communications with appropriate customer support department. Developed a JavaMail component to support the application.

Union Bank, Senior Developer TOPS Application

TOPS, is an intranet web application running on Microsoft IIS using Active Server Pages (ASP), Seagate Crystal Reports, and MS SQL 2000 database. The application automates monitoring and tracking the non-financial aspects of commercial loans and, also, covenant compliance. Developed ASP pages using server-side logic written in VBScript and JScript and extensive client-side logic written in JavaScript. Developed database views, database user-defined functions (UDF), and stored procedures in TSQL for reporting purposes. Coordinated with end users to develop business requirements and reporting specifications. Lead two other developers in the implementation of several reports in Seagate Crystal Reports.

# 1997 - 1999

Union Bank, Senior Developer RACER Application

RACER (Rapid Application, Credit Execution and Reporting), is a Lotus Notes workflow application that automates the approval and routing process for commercial loan applications and renewals.

#### 1994 - 1997

Union Bank, Senior Developer Prospect Tracking PC

Developed and maintained a "fat-client" application written in dBASE IV. The application was a date-tickler used to monitor various aspects of commercial loans. Also during this period, I converted data from the legacy applications and imported it into the new date-tickler application. Also, supported the roll-out of a new customer relationship management vendor application.

#### 1990 - 1993

Union Bank, Senior Developer IBM Sys 36 & PC

Maintained several applications written in RPGII running on 30 different IBM Sys/36 computers on the Bank's wide-area network. The applications communicated with the mainframe using RJE (Remote Job Entry) to upload data and JCL (Job Control Language) to run the mainframe jobs. Additionally, the applications screen-scraped CICS application using SNUF (SNA Upline Facility).

#### 1987 - 1988

Paul Munroe Hydraulics, Systems Manager

High-visibility, hands-on position. Responsible for maintaining HP3000 computer with 120 users and a wide-area network. Programmed in PowerHouse (Quiz, QTP, etc.) Extensive analysis and design with emphasis on directly coordinating with end-users to determine business requirements.

# 1985 - 1987

Self-Employed, Consultant Programmer Analyst

Developed, debugged and maintained interactive and batch applications written in C, xBase, Lotus 1-2-3, COBOL and RPGII; supported and trained end users. Computers used: IBM PC, IBM System 36, and IBM System 34

1983 - 1985

Leadtec Systems Inc., Senior IBM System 36 Programmer Analyst

Application was an interactive piecework payroll system for the apparel industry written in COBOL. Computers used: IBM System 36, IBM PC

1981 - 1983

Germain's Inc., Programmer Analyst

Developed, debugged and maintained interactive and batch applications written in RPGII; supported and trained end users. Computer used: IBM System 34

1979 - 1981

Shirley Software Systems, Programmer Analyst

Developed, debugged and maintained batch FORTRAN programs to handle PERT/CPM scheduling. Computers used: HP 3000, Prime and DEC.

# **Education**

2016

MEAN Stack Development using MongoDB, Express, Angular, and Node

2014

Computer Associates (CA) SiteMinder Product Training

2008

Tridion CMS

2004

Microsoft .NET using C# and Visual Basic

Microsoft .NET using Linux

2000

IBM Visual Age for Java, IBM Education Center

IBM WebSphere 3.0, IBM Education Center

1999

O-O Programming with Java, IBM Education Center

Introduction to Data Modeling using ERWin

1998

Supporting MS Windows NT 4.0 Core Technologies, Infotec Commercial Systems Managing Multiple Priorities and Deadlines, Data-Tech, Inc

1997

Lotus Notes Version 4 Application Development I & II, Infotec Commercial Systems

Lotus Notes Version 4 Systems Management I & II, Infotec Commercial Systems

1	a	a	6
ı	J	J	U

How to Design Effective User Interfaces, Human Factors International, Inc.

Practical Usability Testing, Human Factors International, Inc.

1996

OO Programming with Borland Delphi, Cal Poly Pomona

1995

DCI's Strategies & Tools for Successful Data Warehouses Seminar

1989

HP3000 System Administration, Hewlett Packard

Math Major (incomplete), California Polytechnic State University Pomona

1978

Computer Programming and Operations, Control Data Institute